Okay, so let's just see what I just said
in practice. So I said my number one is
12, my number two is 7. So I'm saying 12
/ 7 and I should get 1 point something.
Um, if we open it up, we can see that I
do in fact get 1.7142857.
And I'm going to stop reading there
because you really don't need to know
all those decimal places. But the point
is seven goes in at least one time. So
that's how you get the full decimal is
if you just do normal division. Now
let's run the modulus operator and let's
see what happens. So instead of doing
the divide sign, we're going to do the
percent sign. The percent sign is found
over the number five on your keyboard.
So shift five. So my num one mod my num
2. And when we run this, we see that the
remainder is five. So why on earth would
you want to do that? Well, um, in one of
the projects I was working with, I had
an app where the user had to submit an
unknown number of items. I needed to
process all of the items, but I didn't
know um how many items they were could
they would submit. It changed every
time. But what I did know is that their
information came in sets of four. So,
what I did is I used a modulus operator
and that looked at um what piece of
information I was on. And every time it
was evenly divisible by four, meaning
when I said item number modulus
um four, if it came out to zero, meaning
there was no remainder in the division,
I knew I was on a new piece of
information. So that's one way you might
use it. Another way people use it is to
figure out if something is even or odd.
They'll take the number mod 2 and if the
result is zero, meaning there's no
remainder, then you know it's evenly
divisible by two and therefore it's
even. Um, so hope that was helpful for
the modulus and I'll see you in the next